In this video, I'm gonna describe the Bayesian Approach to fitting models, using
本视频将通过一个简单的抛硬币的例子 介绍用来拟合模型的贝叶斯方法
a simple coin tossing example. If you're already know about the Bayesian
如果你已经了解过贝叶斯方法
Approach, you can skip this video. The main idea behind the Bayesian Approach
你可以跳过这个视频 贝叶斯方法的主要思想是
is instead of looking for the most likely setting of the parameters of the model, we
不局限于考虑模型参数最可能的取值
should consider all possible settings of the parameters and try to figure out for
我们考虑参数所有可能的取值
each of those possible settings, how probable it is, given the data we
并找出每个取值在给定观测数据的条件下 有多大概率取到
observed. The Bayesian framework assumes that we
贝叶斯框架假设我们对于任何事情
always have a prior distribution for everything.
都有一个先验分布
That is, for any event that you might care to mention, I have to have some prior
也就是对于你任意感兴趣的事情 我都有某个先验的概率
probability that, that event might happen. The problem might be very vague.
这个概率刻画了这个事情发生的可能性 这个先验可能比较模糊
So what's happening is, our data gives us a likelihood term.
我们已有的数据给了我们一个似然项
We combine it with our prior and then we get a posterior.
我们把它和先验分布结合起来 就可以得到一个后验分布
The likelihood term favors settings of our parameters that make the data more likely.
似然项更青睐使得观测数据取得的概率 更高的参数
It can disagree with the prior. And in the limit, if we get enough data,
如果我们能够得到足够的数据 这个参数可能与先验信息不太一致
however unlikely the prior is, the data can overwhelm it.
无论先验信息多么不靠谱 足够的数据都能在一定意义上纠正过来
And in the end, with enough data, the truth will out.
并且最后 有了足够的数据 真实的参数取值就会被找到
That is, even if your prior's wrong, you'll end up with the right hypothesis.
也就说即使你的先验信息是错误的 你都有可能最终获得一个正确的假设
But that may take an awful lot of data if you thought that things were very unlikely
但是这可能会需要海量的数据 你可能会认为这不太可能
under your prior. So let's start with a coin tossing
那么我们从一个抛硬币的例子开始
example. Suppose you don't know anything about
如果你只知道硬币可以被抛
coins except that they can be tossed and when you toss a coin you get either a head
然后抛完要么正面朝上要么反面朝上
or a tail. And we're also going to assume you know
如果我们还假设每次抛硬币
that each time you do that it's an independent decision.
这些事件之间都是相互独立的
So our model of a coin is going to have one parameter P.
那么我们抛硬币的模型将有一个参数P
This parameter P determines the probability that the coin will produce a
P刻画了硬币正面朝上的概率
head. What happens now if we see 100 tosses and
如果100次抛掷
there are 53 heads. What is a good value for P.
有53次正面朝上 那么P的取值应该是多少呢
Well obviously you're tempted to say.53. But what's the justification for that?.
当然你要说P取值是0.53 那么你这么说的理由是什么呢
The frequentest answer, which is also called maximum likelihood, is to pick the
从频率学派的角度讲 这叫做最大似然估计
value of p that makes the observations most probable.
也就是找出使得能够得到观测数据最可能的p
And that value of p is.53. It's not obvious that's true, let's derive
然后这个p取值就是0.53 这个结论并不显然
that. So the probability of a particular
我们推导一下
sequence that contains 53 heads and 47 tails could be written out by writing down
得到53次正面47次反面的概率可以这样表示 每次正面朝上就乘p
p every time you toss a head. And 1-p every time you toss a tail.
每次反面朝上就乘1-p
And then if we collect all the p's together, and all the 1-p's together, we
如果我们把所有p的项放在一起 把所有1-p的项也放在一起
get p^53, and 1-p^47. If we now ask, how does the probability of
那么就得到了p的53次方和1-p的47次方
observing that data depend on p, we can differentiate with respect to p, and we
如果问得到观测数据的概率是怎样依赖于p的 那么我们可以对p求导
get the expression shown here, and if we then set that derivative to zero.
然后得到这样一个表达式 然后我们另导函数为0
We discover that the probability of the data is maximized by setting P to be.53.
我们发现可以发现如果想最大化这个概率 就要令P取值为0.53
So that's maximum likelihood. But there's some problems with using
这就是极大似然方法 但是这里有个问题
maximum likelihood to decide on the parameters of a model.
就在我们使用极大似然 来决定一个模型的参数的时候
Suppose for example, we only toss the coin once and we got one head.
例如我们只抛掷一次硬币 然后我们得到了正面朝上
It doesn't really make sense to say we think the probability of the coin coming
但是我们认为硬币正面朝上的概率
down heads in future is one. That would mean we'd be willing to bet
取值为1这显然是不合理的 不然这就意味着我们也认可了
that infinite odds that it can't come down tails.
硬币抛掷无数次都不可能出现反面朝上的情况
And that seems ridiculous. It's sort of intuitively obvious that a
这看起来也太荒谬了 而且很直观的一个更好的猜测
much better answer is not.5. But how can we justify that.
就是p取值为0.5 但是我们要如何验证这一点呢
More importantly, we can ask, is it reasonable to give a single answer.
更重要的是 我们可以问 只求得一个答案这件事情本身是合理的吗
We don't know much. We don't have much data, and so we're
我们知道的不多 我们没有足够多的数据
unsure about what the value of P is. So what we really ought to do is refuse to
所以我们也不能知道P的取值是多少 所以我们真正应该做的是
give a single answer and instead give a whole probability distribution across
拒绝得到一个单一的答案 而是应该去得到一个概率分布
possible answers. An answer like 0.5 is fairly likely.
这个分布包含了所有可能的答案 一个像0.5这样的答案是很有可能的
An answer like one is maybe still pretty unlikely if we have some prior belief that
一个像1这样的答案是不太可能的
coins come down heads half the time. So, now I'm going to go through an example
如果我们先验地认为有一半的次数会正面朝上 现在我们要开始一个例子
where we start with some prior distribution over parameter values, and
我们从对参数的所有取值有一个先验分布出发
we'll pick a prior distribution that's easy to work with.
这里我们选择一个好处理的先验分布
Not one that necessarily fits what we really believe about commons.
不一定是一个完全符合我们先验认知的分布
And then we'll show how that prior distribution get modified by data if we
然后我们会看到这个先验分布 将会被数据修正
adopt the Bayesian Approach. So, we're gonna start with a prior
如果我们采取贝叶斯方法的话 那么我们将从一个
distribution that says all the different values of p are equally likely.
所有p的取值概率都相同的分布开始
We believe that coins come biased to various extents.
我们相信抛掷硬币存在偏差
And any amount of bias is equally likely. So that some coins come down heads half
或多或少的偏差都有可能存在 所以一些硬币一半的次数正面朝上
the time. Other coins come downs heads all the time.
另一些硬币则是一直正面朝上
And those two kinds of coins are equally likely.
这两种硬币同等可能存在
We now observe a coin coming down heads. So what we do now, is for each possible
我们现在观测到硬币正面朝上 那么我们要做的就是
value of p, we take its prior probability and we multiply by the probability that we
对任意可能的取值p 找到其先验概率
would have observed ahead, given that, that value of p is the correct one.
然后乘以给定该取值时观测到正面朝上的概率
So, for example, if we take the value of P = one which says coins come down heads
例如我们取P为1 则每次硬币都正面朝上
every time then the probability of observing a head would be one.
也就是观测到正面的概率是1
There would be no alternative. And if we take the value of P to be zero
这时就不会出现其他可能 并且如果我们取P为0
the probability of observing a head would be zero.
那么观测到硬币正面朝上的 概率就是0
And if we take it to b.5, the probability of observing having b is.5.
如果我们取P为0.5 那么观测到正面朝上的概率就是0.5
So we take that red line, that's our prior, and we multiply each point on that
所以我们取一条红线 当作我们的先验分布 然后给每个点
by the probability of observing a head according to that hypothesis.
乘以基于这个假设下观测到正面朝上的概率
And now we get the sloping-like, that's a unnormalized posterior.
然后我们就得到了一个倾斜的 未经归一化的后验分布
It's unnormalized because the area under that line doesn't add up to one.
称其未归一化是因为直线下方面积不是1
And of course for a probability distribution, the probabilities of all the
然而对任意的概率分布 其所有可能事件的概率加起来应该是1
alternative events have to add to one. So the last thing we do is re-normalize
所以最后一步就是对后验分布归一化
it. We scale everything up so the area under
我们按比例整理所有概率之后
the curve is one. And now if we started with the uniform pri
曲线下方的面积就是1了 如果我们从均匀分布开始
distribution of the P we end up with this triangular posterior distribution of the P
就会得到一个三角形的分布
having observed one head. Now let's do it again.
这是经过观测一边得到的
And this time let's suppose we get a tail. So, the prior distribution that we start
让我们再来一次 这次我们假设得到反面朝上
with now is the post-serial distribution we had after observing our one head.
那么这时候我们的先验分布 就是刚才观测到正面朝上之后的后验分布
And now, the green line shows the probability that we will get a tail
图中的绿色直线表示了
according to each of those hypotheses that correspond to a value of P.
和P的取值相对应的假设下 我们得到硬币反面朝上的概率
So, for example, if P is one, the probability we would observe at time is
例如如果P是1 那么我们能观测到反面朝上的概率就是0
zero. So we have to multiply our prior by our
我们再次用先验乘以似然
likelihood term. And now we get a curve like that.
然后就得到了这样一个曲线
Then we have to re-normalize to make the area be one.
此外我们还要再次归一化后验分布 使得曲线下方的面积是1
And that's now a posterior distribution, after having observed one head and one
那么这就是我们目前为止的后验分布了 这是在观测到一次正面一次反面后得到的
tail. I notice it's a pretty sensible
注意到这个分布是比较敏感的
distribution. After observing one of each, we know that
在一次正面一次反面的观测后
P can't be either zero or one, and it also seems very sensible that the most likely
P的取值既不是0也不是1 而且最可能的取值是在中间
thing is now in the middle. If we do this again another 98 times, and
如果我们持续做完剩下98次
keep applying the same strategy of multiplying the posterior we had after the
并且持续使用同样的公式 也就是用上次试验后得到的后验分布作为
last task, by the likelihood of observing that event, given the various different
本次的先验分布 然后乘以P取不同值确定的似然函数
settings of the parameter p. And let's suppose we get 53 heads and 47
如果我们最后得到53次正面朝上 47次反面朝上
tails in all. Then we'll end up with a curve that looks
那最后得到的曲线就是这样的
like this. It'll have its mean at 53..
这个分布的均值就是0.53
Because we started with the uniform prior. And it'll be fairly sharply peaked by 53..
因为我们是从均匀分布开始的 所以最后曲线在0.53处有一个尖锐的峰值
But it'll allow other values like 49. is a perfectly reasonable value under this
但是同时也允许像0.49这样的值 也有一个比较合理的取值可能性
curve. Not quite as lengthy as 53., but very
虽然不像0.53这样概率高 但也比较合理
reasonable. Whereas a value of 25. is extremely
但是像0.25这样的取值
unlikely under this curve. So we can summarize all that with base
在这个去曲线下就十分不可能了 我们可以用贝叶斯定理总结
therm. Determine the middle of this equation is
等式中间这一项
the joint probability of a set of parameters W, and some data D.
是关于参数W和数据D的联合分布
And for supervised learning, the data is gonna consist of the target values.
对于监督式学习 数据将包括模型的输出值
So we assume we are given inputs and the data values consist of the target values
所以我们这里假设 输入值和输入值分别对应的输出值
that are associated with those iinputs. That what we observe.
都是给定的 这也是我们观测到的数据
That joint probability can be re-written as the product of an individual
这个联合分布还可以重写为
probability and a conditional probability. So on the right, we're written it as p of
关于单一变量的概率和条件概率的乘积 在右边写为W的概率乘以给定W下D的概率
w times p of d given w, and on the left, I've written it as p of d times p of w
左边写为W的概率乘以给定W下D的概率
given d. Now we can divide both sides by p of d.
在左右两边同时除以D的概率
And this gives us base there, I mean it's usual form.
这就得到了贝叶斯公式的一般形式
Base theorem says that the posterior probability of a particular value of W,
贝叶斯公式说明了特定取值的W 其给定D的后验概率
given the data D, is just the prior probability of that particular value of W
就是取值W的概率再乘以
times the probability given that particular value of W, that you would have
给定W产生D的概率
observed the data you observed. And that has to be normalized by P of D.
并且这个概率要被D的概率归一化处理
The probability of the data which is simply the integral over all possible
数据D的概率可以通过对所有可能的W积分求得
values of W, of P of W, P of D, given W. The bottom line needs to be the sum of the
被积函数是W的概率乘以给定W下D的概率
top line a row of possible values w in order for this to be a probability
线下项的数值应该是 线上项所有W决定的数值的和
distribution that adds to one. Because that p of d has integrated over
因为所有的概率加起来要是1 因为D的概率计算的时候对所有W进行了积分
all possible values of w, it's not affected by picking a particular value of
所以这一项就与W具体的取值无关
w on the left-hand side. So when we're looking for the best value
所以当我们想求一个W使得后验概率最大
of w, for example, we can ignore p of d. It doesn't depend on w.
我们就可以忽略D的概率这一项 因为这一项和W无关
The other two terms on the right-hand side, however, do depend on w.
然而等式右边的其他两项都是依赖于W的 翻译: iChen | 审核: Coursera Global Translator Community